let's see the solution for our
instruction pipelining quiz
we have a five-stage pipeline each stage
takes one clock cycle we have ten
instructions if we do instructions one
at a time with no pipelining each
instruction will need to go through all
five stages it takes five cycles to do
that and then the next instruction can
go and takes five cycles to do that and
so on so we're gonna have five cycles
per instruction times ten instructions
it will be fifty cycles until we are
done
with pipelining remember that the first
instruction will take five cycles to go
through but the next instruction will be
one cycle behind so
it will take one cycle
to get the next instruction one cycle to
get the one after that and so on
so the remaining nine instructions
finish every cycle
overall it takes 14 cycles as you can
see again we have a significant speed up
from using pipelining and just like with
laundry don't forget that it takes some
initial number of cycles to fill the
pipeline only then we can get an
instruction leaving every cycle